Enabled by default linters:
errcheck: Errcheck is a program for checking for unchecked errors in Go code. These unchecked errors can be critical bugs in some cases.
govet: Vet examines Go source code and reports suspicious constructs. It is roughly the same as 'go vet' and uses its passes. [auto-fix]
ineffassign: Detects when assignments to existing variables are not used. [fast]
staticcheck: It's the set of rules from staticcheck. [auto-fix]
unused: Checks Go code for unused constants, variables, functions and types.

Disabled by default linters:
arangolint: Opinionated best practices for arangodb client.
asasalint: Check for pass []any as any in variadic func(...any).
asciicheck: Checks that all code identifiers does not have non-ASCII symbols in the name. [fast]
bidichk: Checks for dangerous unicode character sequences. [fast]
bodyclose: Checks whether HTTP response body is closed successfully.
canonicalheader: Canonicalheader checks whether net/http.Header uses canonical header. [auto-fix]
containedctx: Containedctx is a linter that detects struct contained context.Context field.
contextcheck: Check whether the function uses a non-inherited context.
copyloopvar: A linter detects places where loop variables are copied. [fast, auto-fix]
cyclop: Checks function and package cyclomatic complexity. [fast]
decorder: Check declaration order and count of types, constants, variables and functions. [fast]
depguard: Go linter that checks if package imports are in a list of acceptable packages. [fast]
dogsled: Checks assignments with too many blank identifiers (e.g. x, _, _, _, := f()). [fast]
dupl: Detects duplicate fragments of code. [fast]
dupword: Checks for duplicate words in the source code. [fast, auto-fix]
durationcheck: Check for two durations multiplied together.
embeddedstructfieldcheck: Embedded types should be at the top of the field list of a struct, and there must be an empty line separating embedded fields from regular fields. [fast]
err113: Check errors handling expressions. [auto-fix]
errchkjson: Checks types passed to the json encoding functions. Reports unsupported types and reports occurrences where the check for the returned error can be omitted.
errname: Checks that sentinel errors are prefixed with the `Err` and error types are suffixed with the `Error`.
errorlint: Find code that can cause problems with the error wrapping scheme introduced in Go 1.13. [auto-fix]
exhaustive: Check exhaustiveness of enum switch statements.
exhaustruct: Checks if all structure fields are initialized.
exptostd: Detects functions from golang.org/x/exp/ that can be replaced by std functions. [auto-fix]
fatcontext: Detects nested contexts in loops and function literals. [auto-fix]
forbidigo: Forbids identifiers.
forcetypeassert: Find forced type assertions.
funcorder: Checks the order of functions, methods, and constructors. [fast]
funlen: Checks for long functions. [fast]
ginkgolinter: Enforces standards of using ginkgo and gomega. [auto-fix]
gocheckcompilerdirectives: Checks that go compiler directive comments (//go:) are valid. [fast]
gochecknoglobals: Check that no global variables exist.
gochecknoinits: Checks that no init functions are present in Go code. [fast]
gochecksumtype: Run exhaustiveness checks on Go "sum types".
gocognit: Computes and checks the cognitive complexity of functions. [fast]
goconst: Finds repeated strings that could be replaced by a constant.
gocritic: Provides diagnostics that check for bugs, performance and style issues. [auto-fix]
gocyclo: Computes and checks the cyclomatic complexity of functions. [fast]
godoclint: Checks Golang's documentation practice (godoc). [fast]
godot: Check if comments end in a period. [fast, auto-fix]
godox: Detects usage of FIXME, TODO and other keywords inside comments. [fast]
goheader: Check if file header matches to pattern. [fast, auto-fix]
gomoddirectives: Manage the use of 'replace', 'retract', and 'excludes' directives in go.mod. [fast]
gomodguard: Allow and blocklist linter for direct Go module dependencies. This is different from depguard where there are different block types for example version constraints and module recommendations. [fast]
goprintffuncname: Checks that printf-like functions are named with `f` at the end. [fast]
gosec: Inspects source code for security problems.
gosmopolitan: Report certain i18n/l10n anti-patterns in your Go codebase.
grouper: Analyze expression groups. [fast]
iface: Detect the incorrect use of interfaces, helping developers avoid interface pollution. [auto-fix]
importas: Enforces consistent import aliases. [auto-fix]
inamedparam: Reports interfaces with unnamed method parameters. [fast]
interfacebloat: A linter that checks the number of methods inside an interface. [fast]
intrange: Intrange is a linter to find places where for loops could make use of an integer range. [auto-fix]
iotamixing: Checks if iotas are being used in const blocks with other non-iota declarations. [fast]
ireturn: Accept Interfaces, Return Concrete Types.
lll: Reports long lines. [fast]
loggercheck: Checks key value pairs for common logger libraries (kitlog,klog,logr,slog,zap).
maintidx: Maintidx measures the maintainability index of each function. [fast]
makezero: Find slice declarations with non-zero initial length.
mirror: Reports wrong mirror patterns of bytes/strings usage. [auto-fix]
misspell: Finds commonly misspelled English words. [fast, auto-fix]
mnd: An analyzer to detect magic numbers. [fast]
modernize: A suite of analyzers that suggest simplifications to Go code, using modern language and library features.
musttag: Enforce field tags in (un)marshaled structs.
nakedret: Checks that functions with naked returns are not longer than a maximum size (can be zero). [fast, auto-fix]
nestif: Reports deeply nested if statements. [fast]
nilerr: Find the code that returns nil even if it checks that the error is not nil.
nilnesserr: Reports constructs that checks for err != nil, but returns a different nil value error.
nilnil: Checks that there is no simultaneous return of `nil` error and an invalid value.
nlreturn: Checks for a new line before return and branch statements to increase code clarity. [fast, auto-fix]
noctx: Detects function and method with missing usage of context.Context.
noinlineerr: Disallows inline error handling (`if err := ...; err != nil {`).
nolintlint: Reports ill-formed or insufficient nolint directives. [fast, auto-fix]
nonamedreturns: Reports all named returns.
nosprintfhostport: Checks for misuse of Sprintf to construct a host with port in a URL. [fast]
paralleltest: Detects missing usage of t.Parallel() method in your Go test.
perfsprint: Checks that fmt.Sprintf can be replaced with a faster alternative. [auto-fix]
prealloc: Find slice declarations that could potentially be pre-allocated. [fast]
predeclared: Find code that shadows one of Go's predeclared identifiers. [fast]
promlinter: Check Prometheus metrics naming via promlint. [fast]
protogetter: Reports direct reads from proto message fields when getters should be used. [auto-fix]
reassign: Checks that package variables are not reassigned.
recvcheck: Checks for receiver type consistency.
revive: Fast, configurable, extensible, flexible, and beautiful linter for Go. Drop-in replacement of golint. [auto-fix]
rowserrcheck: Checks whether Rows.Err of rows is checked successfully.
sloglint: Ensure consistent code style when using log/slog. [auto-fix]
spancheck: Checks for mistakes with OpenTelemetry/Census spans.
sqlclosecheck: Checks that sql.Rows, sql.Stmt, sqlx.NamedStmt, pgx.Query are closed.
tagalign: Check that struct tags are well aligned. [fast, auto-fix]
tagliatelle: Checks the struct tags.
testableexamples: Linter checks if examples are testable (have an expected output). [fast]
testifylint: Checks usage of github.com/stretchr/testify. [auto-fix]
testpackage: Linter that makes you use a separate _test package. [fast]
thelper: Thelper detects tests helpers which do not start with the t.Helper() method.
tparallel: Tparallel detects inappropriate usage of t.Parallel() method in your Go test codes.
unconvert: Remove unnecessary type conversions.
unparam: Reports unused function parameters.
unqueryvet: Detects SELECT * in SQL queries and SQL builders, preventing performance issues and encouraging explicit column selection. [fast]
usestdlibvars: A linter that detect the possibility to use variables/constants from the Go standard library. [fast, auto-fix]
usetesting: Reports uses of functions with replacement inside the testing package. [auto-fix]
varnamelen: Checks that the length of a variable's name matches its scope.
wastedassign: Finds wasted assignment statements.
whitespace: Whitespace is a linter that checks for unnecessary newlines at the start and end of functions, if, for, etc. [fast, auto-fix]
wrapcheck: Checks that errors returned from external packages are wrapped.
wsl_v5: Add or remove empty lines. [auto-fix]
zerologlint: Detects the wrong usage of `zerolog` that a user forgets to dispatch with `Send` or `Msg`.
wsl [deprecated]: Add or remove empty lines. [fast, auto-fix]
